Guide to the New York State College of Forestry Pamphlets, 1898-1933
New York State College of Forestry Pamphlets, 1898-1933
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Forestry pamphlets 1898-1933
20-1-401
New York State College of Forestry
1.1 cubic ft.
Printed and typed reports and publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pamphlets produced by the New York State College of Forestry.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
A collection of pamphlets and selected student reports on forestry and lumbering prepared by the New York State College of Forestry at Cornell University, Bernhard E. Fernow, and others pertaining to the College's operation, its experimental forest in the Adirondacks, and the Swenson Suit which resulted in the abandonment of the College's experimental program.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Forestry.; New York State College of Agriculture. Dept. of Forestry.
Subjects:
Forestry schools and education--New York (State)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Announcement of the New York State College of Forestry, Cornell University, 1898 (Box 1)
- Aims and methods of the College of Forestry, B. E. Fernow, 1898 (Box 1)
- First Annual Report of the N.Y.S. College of Forestry, 1899 (Box 1)
- Annual Report of the Director of the N.Y.S. College of Forestry: Progress of Forest Management in the Adirondacks, 1900 (Box 1)
- Beginnings of Professional Forestry in the Adirondacks, B. E. Fernow, 1900 (Box 1)
- Swenson Suit Before the Attorney-General of the State of New York/Papers for the University, 1900 (Box 1)
- Third Annual Report of the Director of the N.Y.S. College of Forestry, 1901 (Box 1)
- Fourth Annual Report of the Director of the N.Y.S. College of Forestry at Cornell University, 1902 (Box 1)
- Fourth Annual Report of the N.Y.S. College of Forestry for the Year 1901, 1902 (Box 1)
- Adirondack Forest Problems, B. E. Fernow, 1902 (Box 1)
- Testimony Before the U.S. Industrial Commission in Forestry Matters, B. E. Fernow, 1902 (Box 1)
- Forest Quarterly, v. 1, No. 1, 1902 (Box 1)
- Report of the New York State College of Forestry of Cornell University, 1903 (Box 1)
- Report of the Director of the N.Y.S. College of Forestry at Cornell University, 1903 (Box 1)
- Swenson Suit before the Attorney-General of the State of New York - Brief in behalf of Brooklyn Cooperage Company, June 1903 (Box 1)
- Swenson Suit before the Attorney-General of the State of New York - Brief in behalf of Brooklyn Cooperage Company, Sept. 1903 (Box 1)
- The Public Interest Involved in the Cornell Forestry Experiment, B. E. Fernow, 1904 (Box 1)
- Report of the Special Committee of the Senate on the Future Policy of the State in Relation to the Adirondacks and Forest Preservation, 1904 (Box 1)
- Twelve Theses on College Forest Management and Brief Statement of Results, B. E. Fernow (Box 1)
- Beginnings of Professional Forestry In the Adirondacks, B. E. Fernow (Box 1)
- Forest Utilization: Report on Lumbering operations near Galeton, Potter County, Pennsylvania, John Donald Lamont, 1913; L5 (Box 2)
- A Woods Operation in the Northern Adirondacks, Edward I. Tinkham, 1915; L10 (Box 2)
- Reports on Pulp and Paper Mills and Band Sawmill, Robert Ernest Perry ('17), 1916; L15 (Box 2)
- Woods and Mill Operations in the Adirondacks in the Vicinity of Tupper Lake, New York, Frederick H. Alfke, Charles Ten Eick, Irvin Bernhardt, S. Charles Lerner (all Class of 1920), 1919; L11 (Box 2)
- Study of the Lumbering Operation of the Emporium Forestry Company, John Nelson Spaeth, 1919; L17 (Box 2)
- Logging and Milling in the Adirondacks, W. B. Apgar, T. T. Buckley, A. S. Herzig, W. W. Simonds, 1920; L14 (Box 2)
- Report on Forest Utilization near Tupper Lake, New York, Samuel Elmer Davis ('23), 1921; L16 (Box 2)
- Forest Utilization in the Adirondacks, George Druckerman, R. Elwood Thompson, Philip G. Wakeley, and Irving Weiselberg, 1922; L19 (Box 2)
- A Report on Forest Utilization, Tupper Lake, New York, Alfred Paul Jahn ('18), 1922; L20 (Box 2)
- A Report Dealing with Forest Utilization in the Vicinity of Tupper Lake, New York, T. B. Colby, W. Johnson, F. I. Righter, R. Slockbower (all Class of 1923), 1922; L18 (Box 2)
- Logging and Milling Reports, D. B. Cook, R. S. Baker, A. M. Ross, J. E. Davis, A. A. Doppel, 1923; L21 (Box 2)
- Logging and Milling: Richwood, West Virginia, W. B. MacMillan, 1923; L22 (Box 2)
- Logging and Milling in the Adirondacks, Willis E. Chase, Charles A. Gillett, Henry P. Howell, Wendall K. Webber, 1924; L23 (Box 2)
- Logging and Milling in the Adirondacks, Paul H. Logan, Donald Weeks, Milford C. Howard, James E. Frazer, 1925; L25 (Box 2)
- Logging and Milling in the Adirondacks, K. B. Spear, David Beatty, W. Y. Niall, 1926; L26 (Box 2)
- Utilization Report Adirondacks, A. G. Sharp, F. G. Davenport, L. H. Hall, C. A. Abell, 1927; L27 (Box 2)
- Logging and Milling in the Adirondacks, Fred Simmons, G. W. Hedden, F. K. Beyer, R. M. Connor, 1928; L28 (Box 2)
- Logging and Milling Reports, Adirondacks, W. R. Silcocks, D. H. Bloomer, L. C. Maisenhelder, John Hanshaw, Darwin Miscall, 1930; L27 (Box 2)
- Adirondack Wood-Using Industries, M. Afanasiev, L. J. Coyne, H. D. Hill, 1932; L31 (Box 2)
- Adirondack Logging and Milling Reports, John S. Andrews, Max Dercum, Paul M. Kihlmire, Edmund Marigliano, 1933; L32 (Box 2)
- "Forest Utilization Report on lumbering Operations Near Galeton, Potter County, Pennsylvania," M. E. Krueger ('14), 1914; R68 (Box 2)
- Study of the White Pine Weevil Damage on the Luther Forest Preserve, Samuel Alexander Graham (G '16), 1916; R3 (Box 2)
- The Basis for Silvicultural Practice in the National Forests of Montana and Idaho, Forestry Dept., Cornell, 1921; R1 (Box 2)
- A Plan for the Development of Popular Forestry Associations in China, C. S. Liu, 1923; R43 (Box 2)
- Sources of Pulp in North America, George J. Druckerman, 1924; R49 (Box 2)
- Forest Utilization notes from courses at Yale Forest School, A. B. Recknagel, n.d.; R69 (Box 2)
- Provisional Working Plan for the Cutting Game Preserve in the North Western Adirondacks, C. U. Forestry Dept., 1915; W5 (Box 2)
- Working Plan for a Forest Tract in Franklin County, NY, C. U. Forestry Dept., 1919; W12 (Box 2)